Guide to the Whitman County Democratic Committee Records 1948-1980
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Whitman County Democratic Committee Records
1948-1980
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
Cage 603
Whitman County Democratic Committee
1 containers. 1 linear feet of shelf space.
Minutes, platforms, voter lists, and subject files of the county organization of the Democratic Party in Whitman County, Washington.
The Whitman County Democratic Central Committee is responsible for the political organization and activity of the Democratic Party in Whitman County. The main duties of the committee are fundraising and canvassing, along with representing the county at state conventions.
Records of the Whitman County Democratic Committee consist of minutes, platforms, vote lists, and subject files. The records span the years 1948-1980, but appear to be incomplete. For example, the years 1948-1954, 1972-1976, and 1977 on are covered by little material. However, the years 1954-1972, and 1976 are well represented.
The materials within the folders have been left in original order, which generally follows chronological order. The folders have been rearranged somewhat to follow a loose chronological order.
This collection is open for research use.
Records of the Whitman County Democratic Committee were acquired by the Washington State University Libraries in 1983 (accession number MS83-01).
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Whitman County Democratic Committee--Archives; Democratic Party (Whitman County, Wash.)--Archives; Democratic Party (Wash.)--Whitman County--History
Whitman County (Wash.)--Politics and government
Political parties--Washington (State)--Whitman County--History; Political parties--Washington (State)--Whitman County--Platforms; Voting registers--Washington (State)--Whitman County--Archives
Government and Politics; Washington (State)
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Whitman County registered voter lists by precinct number
  - 1964 or 1966 – 1, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1964 or 1966 – 2, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - includes list of persons eligible for jury duty - 1, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - includes list of persons eligible for jury duty - 2, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - second copy, includes changes - 1, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - second copy, includes changes - 2, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Pullman voters - 1, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Pullman voters - 2, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Whitman County Democratic Central Committee meeting minutes - includes constitutions and platforms
  - Includes minutes from 1948-1952, 1954-1959 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1966-1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Subject files
  - Dollars for Democrats, 1964 and earlier (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Dollars for Democrats, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Democratic precinct organization (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Whitman County Democratic Party caucus platforms, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Whitman County convention committees, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - General mailing lists, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Democratic county committee notebook (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Memos, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Young Democrats (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Treasurer correspondence (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Washington State Democratic convention guide, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 23)